paloaltoonline.com 2019-05-02

# Privacy Policy | Palo Alto Online |

_Last updated: Monday, January 8, 2018 2:33 PM_

### Privacy Policy 

We respect the privacy of the personal information you give us, such as your name, street address, telephone number and e-mail address, and other personal information you may provide. The following policy is intended to explain how we treat this information. This policy may change from time to time. 

**Traffic data**   
Each time a visitor comes to our web site, our servers collect some basic technical information, including, for example, the visitor's domain name (i.e., the ISP from which the user is logged on). We use software to keep track of traffic to our sites and derive such information as the location from which the traffic originates and which particular pages within the site are being viewed. After we analyze this information, we discard it. We may aggregate information about visitors and traffic and may share the results with advertisers. We will not disclose your individual identity or personally identifiable data that you supply us without your permission. It will only be used for us to contact you. 

**Use of Cookies**  
A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a Web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. We make limited use of cookies to keep track of your visits to our site and to facilitate the logging in process for registered users. 

Other companies that place advertising on our site also have the ability to assign their cookies to you if you visit their sites. This is a process that we do not control.

Additionally, we use services which employ cookies to gather 3rd-party audience data (such as age, gender, and interests), interest-based advertising or information. We do not participate in personally-identifiable information nor do we merge information to build such data repositories.

**E-bulletins**  
If you sign up to receive e-bulletins from PaloAltoOnline.com, you may also receive infrequent other announcements from us. Users can choose to unsubscribe from any new mailing lists we create (opt-out) at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions found in each e-mail. 

**Site Registration**  
If you sign up to become a member of PaloAltoOnline.com, your personally identifiable information (such as name, address, phone number, email address) will be stored in our database. We will not disclose your individual identity or personally identifiable data that you supply us without your permission, except as required by law. 

**Surveys**   
We may conduct voluntary surveys of visitors to the site to collect certain demographic information. This information may be compiled and shared in the aggregate with advertisers and other third parties, but no personal details will be traceable or associated with specific individuals. We may use the e-mail address you provided us for the distribution of other announcements. Users can choose to unsubscribe (opt-out) from any mailing lists we create at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions found in each e-mail. 

**Contests**  
We may sponsor contests or other events from time to time that require the collection, processing and storage of certain contact and demographic information (e.g., place of residence) for use as part of the contest. Sometimes these contests may be jointly sponsored with companies. In that case the user's contact and other information will be shared with the other company only if it is expressly stated in the rules of the contest. 

However, such contests will include the option to receive e-mail from our partners regarding their products or services. If you sign up for such an e-mail list, we will release your e-mail address to our partner for the purpose of such mailings, and only for that purpose. We will not release any of your other personal information to that partner. If you do not sign up for such an e-mail list, our partners will receive no information on you – including your e-mail address – even if you enter the associated contest or promotion.

We retain the right to use your e-mail address collected for the distribution of other announcements. Users can choose to unsubscribe (opt-out) from any mailing lists we create at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions found in each e-mail. 

**Children's Privacy**  
Protecting the privacy of young children is important to us. For that reason, we will not collect or maintain information at our Web site from those actually known to be under 13. The sole exception to this is our mailing lists. If a child under 13 signs up for our newsletter or any of our mailing lists, they will remain a member unless we are asked to remove them by their parent or legal guardian, or they elect to opt-out themselves. 

**Security**  
We take precautions to protect your information both online and offline. All of our sites use SHA-256 encrypted SSL Certificates. When we collect sensitive information (such as credit card data), the information is encrypted and transmitted in a secure way. Users can verify this by looking for a lock icon in the address bar and looking for "https" at the beginning of the address of the Web page.

Further, we do not store credit card data in our database. PaloAltoOnline.com uses a third party provider (Braintree, [https://www.braintreepayments.com](https://www.braintreepayments.com/)) as our vault for storage of such data for our Websites. We never see the data, as it's passed directly to the provider, nor do we have a way of seeing the full information once it's encrypted. 

**Other Disclosure of Personal Information**  
We will not otherwise disclose or make use of personal information without consent of the user except (i) as described in this privacy policy, or (ii) as required by law, court order or as requested by other government or law enforcement authority. This policy does not protect information you post to any online bulletin board, chat room, newsgroup, reviews or other public forum within our sites. 

**Other Sites**   
Our sites contain links to sites on the Internet operated by others. We cannot control and are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such other Web sites. 

**Unsubscribe and Data Removal Policies**  
If you would like to unsubscribe from any mailing list, please follow the instructions at the bottom of the mailing list itself. If you want to remove your name and e-mail address from any of our mailing lists, you can send an e-mail requesting removal to [ webmaster@PaloAltoOnline.com](mailto:webmaster@PaloAltoOnline.com). Please include which list you are asking to be removed from.

**Further questions?**  
If you have any further questions or concerns about our privacy policies and use of personal information, please send them to [ webmaster@PaloAltoOnline.com](mailto:webmaster@PaloAltoOnline.com).
